CONTACT ME AT

- Address: 11 Adenuga St., Ibadan, Oyo, Nigeria.
- ayobamiakomolafe@gmail.com
- https://github.com/ayobamiakomolafe
- https://www.linkedin.com/in/akomolafeayobami-646b1919a/

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Python

SQL

Web Scraping

Data Analysis

Data Visualization

Machine Learning

Deep Learning

SOFT SKILLS

Communication

Collaborative Problem Solving

Teamwork

Time Management

PUBLICATIONS

- Presentation: Use-Case of Baceriophages in Gene Therapy. Phage Virus Assembly Conference 2021.
- Phage-Encoded Endolysins. Abdelrahman, F.;
 Easwaran, M.; Daramola, O.I.; Ragab, S.; Lynch,
 S.; Oduselu, T.J.; Khan, F.M.; Ayobami, A.;
 Adnan, F.; Torrents, E.; Sanmukh, S.; El-Shibiny,
 A. Phage-Encoded Endolysins. Antibiotics 2021,
 10, 124.
- Oduselu TJ, Adesanya OA, Daramola OI,
 Akomolafe AJ, Adewumi OM. Expanding the
 Frontiers of Bacterial Diagnosis through
 Bacteriophage Biotechnology. Trop J Nat Prod
 Res. 2020; 4(11):855-860
- SEAPHAGES CONFERENCE 2021. Complete Genome Sequence Annotation of Microbacterium Bacteriophage Dothraki

AKOMOLAFE AYOBAMI

DATA SCIENTIST

PERSONAL PROFILE

A dedicated fast learner, passionate for Data Science/ Al revolution with 3 years of learning and experience in the field, well skilled in Machine Learning and Deep Learning for modelling, Data Analysis and Visualization for insight generations and good knowledge in SQL.

WORK EXPERIENCE

DATA SCIENCE INTERN

Gradient-Boost | Feb 2021 - Sep 2021

- Completed an immersive 6-months internship program that is centered on Data Science.
- Worked in a team of five people to deliver best projects in due time.

MEMBER AI+ Club Ibadan

Data Science Nigeria | Aug 2020 - Present

- Participated actively in several projects ranging from Data Analysis/ Visualization tasks to Machine Learning Hackathons with great success in all.
- Assisted Team lead in club growth by mentoring beginners in AI.

ANNOTATOR LEAD

Ibadan Bacteriophage Research Team | Jan 2019 - Present

EDUCATIONAL HISTORY

University of Ibadan

Medical Laboratory Science | 2016 - 2022

- Course Highlights (major): Medical lab practices, Biochemistry, Hematology, Clinical Microbiology, Blood-Banking, Chemical Pathology, Histopathology, Supervised Clinical Experience.
- Course Highlights (minor): Bioinformatics and Computational studies

University of Michigan

Python Specialization | 2020

 Relevant Coursework: Python, SQL, DBMS, Web-Scraping.

IBM

Data Science Specialization | 2020

 Relevant Coursework: Data Analysis & Visualization, Machine Learning, Artificial Intelligence with Deep Learning.